<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.1</Accession>
        <Title>Kasuga Shrine Mandala</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: This painting depicts the Kasuga Shrine, located at the foot of the sacred Mount Mikasa in the hills surrounding the city of Nara. A group of Buddhist deities hovers across the sky above a vast vertical expanse of countryside, with an aerial view of shrine. The shrine is dedicated to deities, known as kami, of Japan's native Shinto religion. |  Location created: Japan | Date created: early 14th century CE | Current location: Mary and Jackson Burke Foundation | Medium: Hanging scroll with ink, color, and gold |Measurements: 100.3x39.8cm</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.1</Source>
        <Date_Created>1320</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Shinto painting--Japan | Painting, Japanese--Kamakura-Momoyama periods, 1185-1600 | Mountains in art | Gods in art</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Nara-shi (Japan)</geographicTerms>
        <Genre>hanging scrolls | Kamakura | Shinto</Genre>
        <Century>14th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.2</Accession>
        <Title>Haniwa</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The Haniwa are terracotta clay figures which were made for ritual use and buried with the dead as funerary objects during the Kofun period (3rd to 6th centuries AD). They  were created according to the wazumi technique, in which mounds of coiled clay were built up to shape the figure, layer by layer. They are thought to be a figurine that functions as a connection between the living and dead. | Location created: Kyoto, Japan | Date created: 6th century CE | Current location: Collection of the Tokyo National Museum (Important Cultural Property) | Medium: Earthenware | Measurements: 68.5cm tall</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.2</Source>
        <Date_Created>550</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Ceramic sculpture, Japanese | Haniwa | Art, Japanese--To 794</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Kofun | haniwa | earthenware | terracottas (sculptural works) | funerary objects</Genre>
        <Century>6th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.3</Accession>
        <Title>Main Hall, Inner Shrine, Ise</Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Ise Grand Shrine</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: Ise Grand Shrine, located in the city of Ise in Mie prefecture, Japan, is a Shinto shrine dedicated to the goddess Amaterasu-ōmikami. The architectural style of the Ise shrine is known as shinmei-zukuri, characterized by extreme simplicity and antiquity: its basic principles date back to the Kofun period (250-538 C.E.). It has been ritually rebuilt, alternately on two adjoining sites at 20 year intervals with few breaks since the year 690. Carpenters train for the task from childhood. After the kami is ceremonially escorted to the freshly copied shrine, the old shrine is dismantled.  The shrine is thus constantly renewed while being ancient. In this sense it embodies the Shinto faith.  Photograph by Watanabe Yoshio in 1953. | Location created: Mie Prefecture, Japan | Date created: Last rebuilt 1993</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.3</Source>
        <Date_Created>1993</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Shinto architecture--Japan | Shinto shrines--Japan</Subject>
        <personalNames>Amaterasu (Shinto deity)</personalNames>
        <corporateNames>Ise Daijingū</corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Ise-shi (Japan)--Buildings, structures, etc. </geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Shinto| Kofun | shrines (structures) </Genre>
        <Century>20th century</Century>
        <Spatial>Japan--Ise-shi</Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.4</Accession>
        <Title>Aerial View of Horyuji Compound</Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Karuga-dera</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The temple was originally commissioned by Prince Shōtoku on 607. Rebuilt after a fire in 670, it is the oldest wooden temple in the world. The main compound consists of a courtyard surrounded by covered corridors. Within an asymetrical layout, the large kondo (golden hall) is filled with Buddhist images and is used for worship and ceremonies. The pagoda serves as a reliquary.  | Location created: Nara Prefecture, Japan | Date created: 7th century CE</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.4</Source>
        <Date_Created>650</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Architecture--Japan--History--To 794 | Pagodas--Japan</Subject>
        <personalNames>Shōtoku Taishi, 574?-622?</personalNames>
        <corporateNames>Hōryūji (Ikaruga-chō, Nara-ken, Japan)</corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Nara-ken (Japan)--Buildings, structures, etc. </geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Asuka | kondō | pagodas (buildings)</Genre>
        <Century>7th century</Century>
        <Spatial>Japan-Nara-ken</Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.5</Accession>
        <Title>Hungry Tigress Jataka</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The Tamamushi Shrine is a miniature shrine owned by the Hōryū-ji temple complex of Nara, Japan. Paintings on Buddhist themes cover all four sides of both building and plinth. While both pigmented and incised images are known from a number of tombs of a similar date, the shrine is the only example of Buddhist painting from early seventh-century Japan. The Tiger Jātaka, an episode from the Golden Light Sutra, depicts a bodhisattva removing his upper garments and hanging them on a tree before casting himself from a cliff to feed a hungry tigress and her cubs. | Location created: Panel of the Tamamushi Shrine, Horyuji, Japan |  Date created: c. 650 CE | Current location: Horyuji Treasure House, Nara, Japan | Medium: Lacquer on wood | Measurements: 2.33m tall</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.5</Source>
        <Date_Created>650</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Buddhist painting--Japan | Buddhist shrines--Japan | Buddhism in art | Buddhist art--Japan--Nara-ken | Art, Japanese--To 794</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Asuka | bodhisattva | shrines (structures) | lacquer (coating)</Genre>
        <Century>7th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.6</Accession>
        <Title>Buddha Shaka and Attendant Bodhisattvas in the Horyuji Kondo</Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Shaka Triad of Hōryūji</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator>Tori Busshi</Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description:  The Shaka Triad of Hōryūji is considered Tori's masterpiece. An inscription on the back of the halo states that Empress Suiko (r. 593-629) commissioned the work. Tori's works exemplify Japanese Buddhist art during the Asuka period. His style ultimately derives from that of the Chinese Wei kingdom of the late 4th to 6th century. This style was intended for sculpting rock in caves, and even though Tori and his assistants sculpted in clay for bronze casting, his pieces reflect the Chinese front-oriented design and surface flatness. it conveys peace and softness despite a rigid adherence to stock poses and geometrical features. |  Location created: Japan | Date created: c. 623 CE | Current location: Horyuji, Nara | Medium: Gilt bronze | Measurements: 87.5cm tall</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.6</Source>
        <Date_Created>623</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Bronze sculpture, Japanese | Buddhist sculpture--Japan | Buddhism in art | Buddhist art--Japan | Art, Japanese--To 794 | Buddhas in art</Subject>
        <personalNames>Suiko, Empress of Japan, 554-628</personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Asuka | bodhisattva | shrines | bronzes (visual works)</Genre>
        <Century>7th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.7</Accession>
        <Title>Five-Stringed Lute (Biwa) with Design of a Central Asian Man Playing a Biwa atop a Camel</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: The biwa  is a Japanese short-necked fretted lute, often used in narrative storytelling. The biwa is the chosen instrument of Benten, goddess of music, eloquence, poetry, and education in Buddhism. It is the only existing example of an ancient 5-string lute, which was invented in India and transmitted to China then Japan via the Silk Road. Its plectrum guard features the portrayal of a musician sitting on a camel playing a lute.| Location created: China |  Date created: 8th century CE | Current location: Shosoin, Todaiji | Medium:  Red sandalwood and chestnut inlaid with mother-of-pearl, amber, and tortoiseshell | Measurements: 108.1x30.9x9cm</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.7</Source>
        <Date_Created>750</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Biwa | Musical instruments--Japan </Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre> Tang (Chinese style) | musical instruments </Genre>
        <Century>8th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.8</Accession>
        <Title>Great Buddha Hall (Daibutsuden), Todaiji, Nara</Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Tōdai-ji</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: Tōdai-ji is a Buddhist temple complex, that was once one of the powerful Seven Great Temples, located in the city of Nara, Japan. Its Great Buddha Hall houses the world's largest bronze statue of the Buddha Vairocana, known in Japanese simply as Daibutsu. The original structure was completed in 752 CE, twice destroyed, rebuilt in 1707, extensively restored 1906-1913 and 1973-1980. The temple is a listed UNESCO World Heritage Site as one of the "Historic Monuments of Ancient Nara", together with seven other sites including temples, shrines and places in the city of Nara. Deer, regarded as messengers of the gods in the Shinto religion, roam the grounds freely. | Location created: Nara, Japan | Date created: 752 CE</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.9</Source>
        <Date_Created>752</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Architecture, Japanese--Heian period, 794-1185 | Buddhist architecture--Japan | Buddhist temples--Japan--Nara-ken.</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms>Nara-ken (Japan)--Buildings, structures, etc. </geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Heian | temples (buildings)</Genre>
        <Century>8th century</Century>
        <Spatial>Japan-Nara-ken</Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.9</Accession>
        <Title>The Buddha Shaka, Detail of a Paradise Scene</Title>
        <Alternative_Title></Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description: Tōdai-ji is a Buddhist temple complex, that was once one of the powerful Seven Great Temples, located in the city of Nara, Japan. Its Great Buddha Hall houses the world's largest bronze statue of the Buddha Vairocana, known in Japanese simply as Daibutsu. This detail of an engraved bronze lotus petal from is the original Great Buddha (Daibutsu) statue of the Buddha Birushana. It shows the buddha with a narrower waist, broad shoulders and flowing robes that characterize images of buddha from the Tang Dynasty. | Location created: Japan | Date created: 8th century CE |Current location: Daibutsuden, Todaiji | Medium: Engraved bronze | Measurements: height of petal 200 cm</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.8</Source>
        <Date_Created>750</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Art, Japanese--Heian period, 794-1185 | Engraving, Japanese | Buddhist art--Japan | Buddhas in art | Buddhism in art</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Heian | engraving (action)</Genre>
        <Century>8th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
    <row>
        <Accession>15.8493-12.10</Accession>
        <Title>Womb World Mandala</Title>
        <Alternative_Title>Taizokai Mandala</Alternative_Title>
        <Creator></Creator>
        <Contributors></Contributors>
        <Description>Description:  The Womb World (Taizokai) Mandala represents the cosmos of Dainichi Nyorai's eternal and all-encompassing enlightenment. The idea of "womb" implies that this universal enlightenment is the all-embracing principle underlying and nurturing all phenomena. The mandala, in the shape of a long rectangle, consists of twelve sections or courts filled with 414 Buddhas and Bodhisattvas, around a central court in which Dainichi sits on a lotus throne. Above the lotus is a triangle, representing absolute wisdom. Beneath the lotus are the five great kings of wisdom. This mandala would have been used for teaching as well as for meditation practice. | Location created: Japan | Date created: late 9th century CE | Current location: Toji, Kyoto, Japan | Medium: Hanging scroll with colors on silk | Measurements: 1.83x1.54m</Description>
        <Source>Stokstad 12.10</Source>
        <Date_Created>870</Date_Created>
        <Type>Image</Type>
        <Format>Image/tiff</Format>
        <Subject>Painting, Japanese--Heian period, 794-1185 | Buddhist art--Japan | Buddhas in art | Buddhism in art | Mandala in art</Subject>
        <personalNames></personalNames>
        <corporateNames></corporateNames>
        <geographicTerms></geographicTerms>
        <Genre>Heian | hanging scrolls | mandalas</Genre>
        <Century>9th century</Century>
        <Spatial></Spatial>
    </row>
</root>